skoda-auto.com 2014-06-27

# Privacy Statement - ŠKODA

## Declaration of personal data protection principles at the ŠKODA AUTO website

​ **ŠKODA AUTO pays great attention to the protection of personal data. This statement on personal data protection principles clarifies the method of gathering and use of personal data obtained from users of the ŠKODA AUTO internet application (hereinafter the “Website”). ŠKODA AUTO does not gather any personal data that the users do not provide** **themselves voluntarily.**

**Gathering of personal data**  
If ŠKODA AUTO needs data that enables it to identify you (personal data) or contact you for the purpose of providing a product or service you have requested (e.g. information about Company products and services, participation in competitions, ordering of email newsletters, connection to a premium website or limitedaccess service, registration for an event, purchasing, downloading or registering ŠKODA AUTO products), we will ask you for such data. Data that ŠKODA AUTO gathers in connection with your person can contain your name and surname, your title, company or organization name, work email and telephone number, work or home address, information about work position, other company information and/or your credit card details.

The website can gather certain information about visits by users, e.g. the name of your internet service provider and the IP address through which users access the internet, the date and time of their access to the website, the sites from which they open the website and the internet address from which they visit the ŠKODA AUTO website. Such information is used to analyze trends, administer and innovate a website and also to gather information about hardware and software for the purpose of providing the requested service.

ŠKODA AUTO provides website users with the opportunity to directly cooperate with their employees, experts and workers, so that it is possible to share knowledge and news about ŠKODA AUTO products and related technologies. If you want to stop your email address or other personal data being gathered and used by third parties without your consent, we recommend that, when putting your email address or other personal data in discussion groups, conversations or other publicly available forums, you do so with increased caution. Further information and instructions for the safe use of ŠKODA AUTO technical communities is given below.

 **Use of Personal Data** Personal data gathered at this website will be used for personification and to provide the products and services that you requested or to which you consented. ŠKODA AUTO can use personal data to provide better quality customer services, to innovate its website and all related ŠKODA AUTO products and services, and to simplify the use of this website, which can be achieved by eliminating the necessity of repeatedly inputting the same information and having the website adapt itself to the user’s specific preferences and interests. The information gathered by the website can be used for the purpose of obtaining comprehensive information about contacts with ŠKODA AUTO related to information gathered using other ŠKODA AUTO services.

You agree that we can use your personal data to provide you with important information about a product or service that you use, including important updates and warnings. With your consent we can also send you information about other ŠKODA AUTO products and services and share information with our partners, who can also send you information about ŠKODA AUTO products and services.

For research purposes we can combine information about visitors to the website with anonymous demographic information. We can use such information to increase the attractiveness of content. In such sections of the website with restricted access we can, with your consent, combine information about visits to the website with your personal information, to provide you with content adapted directly for you. 

In some cases ŠKODA AUTO provides certain services (such as web hosting, packaging, sending and delivering prizes, replies to customers’ questions about products and services and information about our products, special offers and other new services) through another company. We only provide these companies with the personal data that are necessary to implement a specific service. In addition, we require them to handle the information thoroughly in accordance with the relevant provisions of Act on Some Information Society Services, No. 480/2004 Coll., and not use them for other purposes.

ŠKODA AUTO can disclose personal data to third parties only in the following cases, when it is ordered or enabled by the law or in good faith that such action is necessary to: (a) comply with the law of the country in question and the legal procedures of ŠKODA AUTO; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of ŠKODA AUTO and its websites; or (c) in urgent cases to protect the safety of ŠKODA AUTO employees and business partners, ŠKODA AUTO product and service users and the public.

Personal data gathered at the website can be stored and processed in a country in which ŠKODA AUTO and its branches, affiliates, or representatives have the relevant facilities. 

**Checks on personal data**  
Unless this declaration provides otherwise, the personal data you provide at this website will not be communicated outside ŠKODA AUTO and its branches and affiliates. You have access to your personal data and you can choose the method in which you are contacted, as described below. 

**Access to personal data   **  
Personal data and contact preselection that you have chosen at this website can be viewed and any changes made using the “Central Identification Service” (hereinafter CIS) at the ŠKODA AUTO website. Before personal information is displayed, you will be asked to input the entry data and password.

At the CIS centre you can:

  * Display, alter and cancel personal data that you have already input at the website;
  * Choose whether you want to receive information of a marketing character from the website;
  * Register for or cancel newsletters about our products and services.

 **Personal Data Security**  
ŠKODA AUTO pays great attention to personal data security. With the help of a whole number of security technologies and procedures we help protect your personal data from unauthorized access, use or publication.

 **Cookies**  
We use cookies at the website to ensure the integrity of the registration process and enable users to personally modify the website. A cookie is a small text file placed on the hard disk by the website server. The file cannot be misused to run programs or put viruses into a computer. Cookies are uniquely allocated to you and can only be read by the web server in the domain that issued the cookie to you.   
One of the primary functions of a cookie file is to save you time. If, for example, you adapt a website or browse it, on subsequent visits the cookie will remind the website of specific information about your preferences. This simplifies the process of displaying the relevant content, facilitates navigation at the website, etc. As soon as you return to the web server, information input earlier can be read, so that it is easier for you to use the website’s functions that you have already adapted.

When delivering a cookie to our website, assistance can be provided by website signals (beacons) known as clear gif technology. This technology is a tool that we use for compiling summary statistical data about the website’s use, such as information about how many users at the website have chosen key elements (e.g. links or graphics). We can communicate summary statistical data about the website to partner companies and the public. 

You can automatically accept or reject cookies. Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually set a browser to reject them. If you reject cookies, you will probably not be able to make full use of the interactive functions of the ŠKODA AUTO website.  
This website uses the ŠKODA CIS website for registration. If you want to register, you will be asked for your user name and password. Registration will enable you to access many other websites and related services. If you register using the CIS service, also register at the ŠKODA AUTO website and open a ŠKODA CIS account.

 **Changes in personal data protection principles**  
We may update this declaration in case of need. If this happens, we will alter the last update date in this declaration. We will inform you of amendments to this declaration in a notice we place on our website’s homepage or send directly to registered users. We recommend regularly viewing this declaration, so that you are kept informed of how we help protect the personal data you have made available to us. Further use of this service means you consent to the declaration about the protection of personal data and its updates. 

**Contract information**  
If you think that ŠKODA AUTO has not complied with this declaration, please contact us by email at the following address: [info@skoda-info.cz](mailto:info@skoda-info.cz). If your complaint is legitimate, we will identify the problem and then resolve it.
